Guide to the Hans Bethe papers, ca. 1931-1995
Bethe, Hans papers,
- Series V. Correspondence
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical
    - C (1982) (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - C-D (1991-92) (Box 95, Folder 19)
    - Stirling Colgate (1991) (Box 97, Folder 23)
    - Committee on the Penetration of Charged Particles in Matter (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Conference on Cosmic Radiaton (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - D (Box 67, Folder 42)
    - D (Box 70, Folder 18-20)
    - D (1980-86) (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - de Hoffman re. book (Box 70, Folder 21-22)
    - Detroit Edison Company (Box 70, Folder 23-24)
    - E (Box 67, Folder 43)
    - E (Box 70, Folder 25)
    - E (1984-86) (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists (Box 70, Folder 26)
    - F (Box 67, Folder 44)
    - F (Box 70, Folder 27-34)
    - F (1982-83) (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - F-H (1985-86) (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - F - including Federation of American Scientists (FAS)(1956-65) (Box 83, Folder 12-13)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 70, Folder 35)
    - Foster, John (Box 67, Folder 47)
    - G (Box 67, Folder 49)
    - G (Box 70, Folder 36-38)
    - G (1986-88) (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Garwin (1987-92) (Box 94, Folder 10-11)
    - Garwin (1991) (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - General Electric (1946-54) (Box 70, Folder 39-40)
    - Professor Gibbs (Box 70, Folder 41)
    - Graduate School: Cornell University (Box 70, Folder 42)
    - H (Box 67, Folder 50)
    - H (Box 70, Folder 43-46)
    - H (1986-87) (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - H-L (1987-90) (Box 90, Folder 45)
    - Hudson Institute (Box 67, Folder 51)
    - H. Hoerlin: Correspondence, Talks (Box 67, Folder 52)
    - D. Hill: Correspondence (Box 67, Folder 53)
    - Hydrogen Bomb Correspondence (1950) (Box 70, Folder 47)
    - I (Box 67, Folder 54)
    - I (Box 70, Folder 48)
    - International Conference on Theoretical Physics: Japan (1953) (Box 70, Folder 49)
    - International Conference in Nuclear Physics: Glasgow (1954) (Box 70, Folder 50)
    - Inquiries (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - J (Box 67, Folder 55)
    - J (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - J (1987-88) (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - K (Box 67, Folder 56)
    - K (Box 71, Folder 3-5)
    - K (1983-85) (Box 87, Folder 42)
    - K-N (1984-86) (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Knolls Atomic Power Laboratory (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - L (Box 67, Folder 57)
    - L (Box 71, Folder 7-10)
    - L (1982-84) (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Library of Congress (Box 67, Folder 58)
    - Dr. E. Long: Correspondence (Box 67, Folder 59)
    - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory (1946-49) (Box 71, Folder 11-12)
    - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory (1950-55) (Box 71, Folder 13-15)
    - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - M (Box 67, Folder 61-62)
    - M (1946-49) (Box 71, Folder 17-18)
    - M (1950-51) (Box 71, Folder 19-22)
    - M (1950-54) (Box 71, Folder 23-24)
    - M-P (1991) (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Maximon (1948-54) (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 71, Folder 25)
    - Fort Monmouth Investigations (Box 71, Folder 26)
    - N (Box 67, Folder 63)
    - N (Box 71, Folder 27-28)
    - National Academy of Sciences (Box 71, Folder 29-31)
    - National Bureau of Standards: ASTIN (Box 71, Folder 32-33)
    - National Committee on Atomic Information (Box 71, Folder 34-35)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 71, Folder 36)
    - National Research Council/National Bureau of Standards (Box 71, Folder 37)
    - Nuclear Science Committee (National Research Council) (Box 71, Folder 38)
    - New York University Annual Symposium (1954) (Box 71, Folder 39)
    - Nuclear Development Associates Reports (Box 71, Folder 40)
    - Nuclear Development Associates (Box 71, Folder 41)
    - NEPA (Nuclear-Energy Propulsion for Aircraft) Project (Box 71, Folder 42-43)
    - NEPA Oak Ridge Consultant Contract (Box 71, Folder 44)
    - O (Box 67, Folder 64)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratory (Box 71, Folder 45)
    - Office of Naval Research (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - P (Box 67, Folder 66)
    - P (1986) (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Sen. R. Packwood (Box 67, Folder 67)
    - Dr. R. Parmenter (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Patents (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - The Physical Review (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Q (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Q-T (1987-91) (Box 90, Folder 46)
    - R (Box 67, Folder 68)
    - R (Box 72, Folder 11-15)
    - R (1986) (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Recommendations (Box 72, Folder 16-19)
    - Reprint Mailing List (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Reservations (Box 67, Folder 69)
    - Reservations (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Resettlement Campaign for Exiled Professionals - Report (1951) (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - S (1946-48) (Box 72, Folder 23-24)
    - S (1949-54) (Box 72, Folder 25-27)
    - S (1949-68) (Box 72, Folder 28-30)
    - S (1968-71) (Box 67, Folder 72)
    - S (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Scientific American (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Dr. G. Seaborg (Box 67, Folder 70)
    - Sigma Xi (Box 72, Folder 31)
    - Solvay Conference (1948) (Box 72, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence re: Stanford Conference on Nuclear Sizes and Density Distribution, 1957 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - State Department Expenses (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Dr. V. M. Strutinsky (Box 67, Folder 71)
    - J. Swanson (1954) (Box 72, Folder 33)
    - Symposium on Recent Advances in Science (1954) (Box 72, Folder 34)
    - T (Box 68, Folder 4-5)
    - T (Box 72, Folder 35-36)
    - T (1987) (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - T (1984-85) (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - John Tate (editor Physical Review 1948-49) (Box 72, Folder 37)
    - U (Box 72, Folder 38)
    - U (1989-91) (Box 91, Folder 25-26)
    - U, V (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - U, W, Y (1983-86) (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - U-Z (1990-91) (Box 91, Folder 29)
    - University Notices, Correspondence (Box 72, Folder 39-40)
    - V (Box 72, Folder 41)
    - V Correspondence and Miscellaneous (1955-64) (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re: Frank von Hippel (1972-73) (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - W (Box 68, Folder 7-8)
    - W (Box 72, Folder 42-45)
    - Dr. Warren Weaver (Box 72, Folder 46)
    - V. Weisskopf (Box 72, Folder 47)
    - E. P. Wigner (Box 72, Folder 48)
    - John Wiley and Sons (Box 72, Folder 49-51)
    - Y (Box 72, Folder 52)
    - Yalta: Lack of Communication on Bomb (New York Times Letter to the Editor) (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Z (Box 72, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence - Chronological
    - Correspondence (1933-35) (Box 69, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence (1936) (Box 69, Folder 3-4)
    - Correspondence (1937) (Box 69, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence (1938) (Box 69, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence (1939) (Box 69, Folder 9-10)
    - Correspondence (1940) (Box 69, Folder 11-12)
    - Correspondence (1942) (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence (1948) (Box 68, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence (1961) (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence (1962-63) (Box 83, Folder 21-23)
    - Correspondence (1963-64) (Box 83, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence (1964-65) (Box 83, Folder 27-29)
    - Correspondence and misc. (1971-72) (Box 83, Folder 32-36)
    - Correspondence (1969-70) (Box 69, Folder 24-29)
    - Correspondence (1974) (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (1980-81) (Box 82, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence (1981) (Box 78, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence (1983-84) (Box 82, Folder 40-41)
    - Correspondence (1984) (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence (1985) (Box 93, Folder 49)
    - Faxes sent (1992) (Box 95, Folder 20)
- Series VI. Awards/Honoraria
  - Awards
    - Awards (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Vannevar Bush Award (1985) (Box 88, Folder 28)
    - Einstein Peace Prize - Chicago Talk (1992) (Box 95, Folder 23)
    - Enrico Fermi Award (1961) (Box 67, Folder 48)
      - Correspondence re: nomination for Fermi Award (1958-60) (Box 83, Folder 17)
      - Fermi award, Telle, others - Correspondence (1961-62) (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Max-Planck Medal (1992) (Box 97, Folder 29)
    - Nobel Prize (1967)
      - Nobel Lecture, See also Nobel Prize acceptance speech, 21-53 (Box 68, Folder 67)
      - Calculations Preparing Nobel Lecture (Box 76, Folder 40)
      - Nobel Letters (1967) (Box 96, Folder 10)
      - Nobel Congratulations (1967-68) (Box 96, Folder 11-16)
        Includes telegraph from President Lyndon B. Johnson.
  - Honoraria
    - American Academy of Achievement (1992) (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Cambridge Philosophical Society, Honorary Membership (1962) (Box 79, Folder 31)
    - Certificate of Membership in Franklin Institute (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Oxford University Honorary Degree (not accepted)(1967) (Box 100, Folder 1)
- Series VII. Works by Others
  - Papers/articles/lectures
    - Papers/Pamphlets: Drucksachen insber Bank (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Papers by others on Polarization (Box 63, Folder 33)
    - Paper: Moszkowski (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Ablation (Box 68, Folder 11-12)
    - Talk by A. Kantrowitz at Cornell (Box 68, Folder 40)
    - Outline of Talk by H. M. Agnew (Box 68, Folder 56)
    - H. Dehmelt - off-prints (Box 76, Folder 32)
    - Henry Smyth - free speech (1950) (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - W.D. Arnett, "The Physics of Gravitational Collapse: an overview" - plus tables (1980) (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Calculations by Gerry Brown, May-June 1981 (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Calculations, Gerry Brown, 1981-82 (Box 78, Folder 34)
    - J. Lattiner, EOS (Box 78, Folder 25)
    - Reprints (1982) (Box 78, Folder 27)
    - Neutrinos from the Sun - papers and correspondence (Box 79, Folder 30)
    - Mott on Science and Defense (Box 82, Folder 32)
    - Postol: Fires from Nuclear Attacks (1986) (Box 82, Folder 46)
    - Lists of Others' Publications (1980) (Box 84, Folder 26)
    - Project COWBOY Final Report: "Seismic Ground Effects from Couples and Decoupled Shots in Salt," by D.S. Carder and W.V. Mickey (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - H. Überall (1985) (Box 88, Folder 27)
    - Natividad Carpentero Santamaria (1989) (Box 89, Folder 31)
    - Überall Lecture Notes: Short course on Vector Inverse Methods in Radar-Target-Clutter Imaging (1986) (Box 90, Folder 23)
    - Memoir by Jane Wilson[?] wife of Robert Wilson (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Memoir by Jane Wilson[?] wife of Robert Wilson (Box 92, Folder 45)
    - Silverman (Box 92, Folder 30-31)
    - Brandow, Bruecker on Pandha (1976) (Box 92, Folder 19)
    - Tsipis: Analysis of Dense Pack Vulnerabilities (MX) (Box 93, Folder 28)
    - Problems in Theoretical Physics - NSF Proposal (1991) (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Edmonds (1970) (Box 96, Folder 20)
    - Hoerlin - High-Altitude Tests (1976) (Box 96, Folder 26)
    - Postol: "Bombers can get up" (1984) (Box 96, Folder 38)
    - Teller's Answer to Bethe's H-Bomb History (1991) (Box 97, Folder 24)
  - Books
    - Introduction to Meson Theory Advanced; Quantum Mechanics (Box 65, Folder 30-31)
    - Proceedings on the Conference on the Physics of Breeding (1959) (Box 74)
    - The Ionization of Gas Mixtures in Stellar Interiors I and II, G. Keller and R. Meyerott (1957) (Box 74)
    - Report of an International Conference on Elementary Particles (1950) (Box 74)
    - Neutron Physics: A Course of Lectures, E. Fermi (1946) (Box 74)
    - The Cosmic Ray Intensity Above the Atmosphere Near the Geomagnetic Pole, J. Van Allen (1953) (Box 74)
    - Second-Quantized Theory of Spin 1/2 Particles in Non-Relativistic Limit, R. K. Osborn (1951) (Box 74)
    - Effects of Radioactive Disintegrations on Inner Elections of the Atom, J. S. Levinger (1952) (Box 74)
    - The Electromagnetic Properties of Pirac Particles, L. L. Foldy (Box 74)
    - Introduction to Quantum Electrodynamics, Lludwig and Süssmann (1950) (Box 74)
    - Proceedings of the Rochester Conference on Meson Physics, A. Messiah and H. Noyes (1952) (Box 74)
    - Rochester Conference on High Energy Physics,, Table of Contents (Box 74)
    - Production of Pi Mesons at Relativistic Nucleon Energies, R. E. Marshak (1951) (Box 74)
    - Review of Work on Artificially Produced Meson, H. Bradner (1949) (Box 74)
    - Problems in Cosmic Ray Physics, M. Schein (1946) (Box 74)
    - Pion-Nucleon Scattering Wave Functions, Kalos and Dalitz (1955) (Box 74)
    - The Equation of State of Air, K. Fuchs and R. E. Peierls (Box 74)
    - Numerical Methods for Solving Linear Systems and Applications to Elliptic Difference Equations, C. Lee and P. Stone (1959) (Box 74)
    - The TDC Code, B. Carlson, C. Lee, and J. Worlton (1960) (Box 74)
    - The DSN Code, B. Carlson, C. Lee, and J. Worlton (1960) (Box 74)
    - Numerical Solution of Transient and Steady-State Neutron Transport Problems, B. Carlson (1959) (Box 74)
    - The DSN and TDC Neutron Transport Codes, B. Carlson, C. Lee, and J. Worlton (1960) (Box 74)
    - Meson Theory of Nuclear Forces, W. Pauli (not Los Alamos) (1944) (Box 74)
    - The Chemical Kinetics of the Normal Atmosphere, M. H. Bortner (1961) (Box 74)
    - Free Molecular Heat Transfer in the Ionoshpere, L. Gilbert, S. Scala (1961) (Box 74)
    - Theoretical Analysis for the Mechanical Spallation of a Typical Charring Ablation During Re-entry, R. Mathieu (1963) (Box 74)
    - Chemical Kinetics of the Normal Atmosphere, M. H. Bortner (1963) (Box 74)
    - The Vaporization of Graphite, TiC, ZrC, and HfC, C. Vidale (1961) (Box 74)
    - The Density Structure of the Upper Atmosphere of Mars, D. Vachon (1962) (Box 74)
    - Theory of Hypersonic Luminar Stagnation Region Heat Transfer in Dissociating Gases, S. Scala and D. Sampson (1963) (Box 74)
    - Heat Transfer in Hypersonic Flow with Radiation and Chemical Reaction, S. Scala and D. Sampson (1963) (Box 74)
    - Effect of Turbulence Intermittency on the Scattering of Electromagnetic Waves by Underdense Plasmas, K. T. Yen (1964) (Box 74)
    - Flow Equations for a Chemically Reacting Plasma, R. Thomas, Jr. (1965) (Box 74)
    - Determination of Macroscopic Velocities from Line Profile Asymmetries, J. Kulander (1964) (Box 74)
    - Fine Structure of the Hydrogen Atom, W. Lamb, Jr. and R. Retherford (Box 74)
    - Theoretical Interpretation of Proton-Proton Scattering, J. Jackson (1949) (Box 74)
    - On the Convergence of Born Expansions, W Kohn (Box 74)
    - Radiant Heading of Semi-Transparent Materials, J. Boehringer and R. Spindler (1961) (Box 74)
    - Radiative Correction to the Angular Distribution of Nuclear Recoils from Electron Scattering, L. I. Schiff (1951) (Box 74)
    - Meson Theoretical Interpretation of Proton-Proton Scattering, N. Tzoar, R. Raphel, and A. Klein (Box 75)
    - Deuteron Photodisintegration in the Medium Energy, G. Kramer and C. Werntz (Box 75)
    - Nucleosynthesis in Supernovae, F. Hoyle (1960) (Box 75)
    - On Equation of State of Uranium at Low Densities and Temperatures, R. Cowan (1960) (Box 75)
    - The International Control of Atomic Energy, Report to UN's Atomic Energy Commission (1947) (Box 75)
    - Report of the International Physics Conference, O. Kofoed-Hansen, P. Kristensen, M. Scharff, editors (Box 75)
    - Recent Developments in High Energy Physics, R. Serbet (1950) (Box 75)
    - Pi-Mesonen und Quantisierte Foldtheorien, G. Lüders, R. Oehme, and W. Thirring (1951) (Box 75)
    - Coulomb Functions for Reactions of Protons and Alpha Particles with the Lighter Nuclei, J. Bloch, M. Hull, A. Broyles, W. Bouricius, B. Freeman, and G. Breit (Box 75)
    - Slow Neutron Resonance Spectroscopy I,U238, J. Rosen, J. Desjardins, J. Rainwater, W. Havens (1959) (Box 75)
    - Multiple Scattering of Waves, M. Lax (1950) (Box 75)
    - Meson Theory, R. Serber (1951) (Box 75)
    - A Review of Nuclear Explosion Phenomena Pertinent to Protective Construction, H. Brode (1964) (Box 75)
    - Magneto-Hydrodynamic Shocks, F. de Hoffman and E. Teller (1950) (Box 75)
    - The Nth Country Problem: A Worldwide Survey of Nuclear Weapons Capabilities, W. Davidson, C. Hohenemser, M. Kalkstein (1958) (Box 75)
    - Documents of Second PUGWASH Conference of Nuclear Scientists (1958) (Box 75)
    - Theoretical Discussion of a Small Homogeneous Enriched Reactor, R. F. Christy (1946) (and other classified documents) (Box 75)
    - Investigation into the United States Atomic Energy Project (1949) (Box 75)
    - [Cornell University] (Box 75)
    - The Cornell Bev Synchrotron (1956) (Box 75)
    - Proposal Submitted by Cornell University for Financial Assistance in Procurement of a Nuclear Training Reactor (1958) (Box 75)
    - Lectures on Dispersion Relations at Cornell University, J. Hamilton (1957) (Box 75)
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous
  - Personal
    - Personal Papers (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Stock Holdings (Box 67, Folder 37)
    - Clippings for 60th Birthday (Box 68, Folder 49)
    - 60th Birthday (Box 68, Folder 50)
    - Bethe interview (Box 68, Folder 72)
    - Bethe Security Clearance (1969) (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Biographical material (1983-85) (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Personal (1956-67) (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Calendars (1985-86) (Box 88, Folder 34-35)
    - Bethe Birthday Lunch (1986) (Box 90, Folder 25)
    - Bethe Biographical Material (1963-75) (Box 93, Folder 15)
    - Interview with Rose Bethe (1986) (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Articles in Physics Today and Cornell Chronicle about Bethe's life (2005) (Box 109)
    - Memorial card with inscription by Rose Bethe to Dale Corson (2005) (Box 109)
    - Packet celebrating life of Hans A. Bethe (Box 109)
    - Personal documents from family, mainly on their two cats (Box 112, Folder 31)
    - Bethe travel documents, including passport, 1930s-1940s (Box 112, Folder 32)
    - Rose Bethe's school reports and passport, 1930s (Box 112, Folder 33)
    - Bethe's 95th birthday letter book (Box 112, Folder 34)
    - Souvenir pamphlets from Europe, November 3-17, 2008 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - General
    - Miscellaneous (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Reviews for Physical Review (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Miscellany on Killian Committee (education) (Box 65, Folder 4-5)
    - General Dynamics - General Atomics - General (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Early History of the Physical Sciences Study Committee at MIT, including the Cornell Report on a High School Course in Physics and Chemistry (1956-57) (Box 65, Folder 8-9)
    - Letters of Recommendation (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Comments and Reviews (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - "Die Lawaine" (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Reprint list (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - Conferences and Grants (mid-late 1930's) (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists - Papers/Correspondence /Miscellany (Box 65, Folder 17-20)
    - History of the Computation Laboratory (Box 65, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous photographs and reprints (Box 65, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous reprints (Box 65, Folder 47)
    - Article on Many-Body Problem (Box 65, Folder 48)
    - Proceedings of the Conference on Penetration of Charged Particles (Box 65, Folder 49)
    - General Atomic (Box 65, Folder 50)
    - Physics Humor Magazine in German (Box 65, Folder 51)
    - Photograph: Governing board of American Institute of Physics (1956) (Box 65, Folder 52)
    - President's Science Advisory Committee (Box 65, Folder 53)
    - Varied Papers and Correspondence (Box 65, Folder 54)
    - Clippings I (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Clippings II (Box 66, Folder 15-17)
    - Various Papers (Box 67, Folder 38-39)
    - Safe Miscellany (Box 67, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings and Correspondence: Recommendations (Box 68, Folder 52-53)
    - Association of Scientists of Cornell University (Box 69, Folder 45-46)
    - R. R. Wilson: Recommendation for National Medal of Science, talk in his honor (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Symposium, U. of Washington (1985) (Box 76, Folder 33)
    - Visit, UC Berkeley (1985) (Box 76, Folder 34)
    - General Politics (1954-68) (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous (1961-62) (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper clippings (1958) (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence to/from Robert R. Wilson (1962-64) (Box 83, Folder 24)
    - Robert R. Wilson - expense accounts (1964-65) (Box 83, Folder 26)
    - Travel expenses - Los Alamos National Laboratory (1980) (Box 84, Folder 27)
    - News Clippings (1958-61) (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Autographs (1969) (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Travel Expenses (1975-78) (Box 85, Folder 12-13)
    - Requests for Off-prints (Box 86, Folder 1984-85)
    - Clippings (1977-84) (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Recommendation of B.D. McDaniel for National Medal of Science (1980-86) (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Memory typewriter (1982-84), Files include documents produced by memory typewriter, including letters of recommendation (Box 87, Folder 19-20)
    - Canon Copier (1983-84) (Box 87, Folder 40)
    - Clippings (1985-86) (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Canon AP550-II Electronic Typewriter (1988) (Box 89, Folder 21)
    - Bethe's Nominations for Wolf Prize (1982-87) (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Addresses (1982-87) (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Robert R. Wilson (1983-84) (Box 90, Folder 10-11)
    - Richard L. Garwin (1986) (Box 90, Folder 22)
    - Prof. Salpeter (1986-87) (Box 90, Folder 30)
    - Roger Smith (1987) (Box 90, Folder 40)
    - Venda cards (1988) (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - LNS Journal Club (1990) (Box 91, Folder 27)
    - Mehra, Jagdish (1991) (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Marshall, Bob (1991) (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Expense account (1992) (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Typesetting Mathematics (Box 92, Folder 32)
    - Curricula Vitae (Box 92, Folder 33)
    - Personnel Security (Box 92, Folder 34)
    - Vitae/Publications in alpha order (Box 92, Folder 40)
    - Addresses (Box 92, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 92, Folder 46-47)
    - Expenses (1980-90) (Box 93, Folder 25)
    - Los Alamos (1985) (Box 93, Folder 46)
    - Livermore (1985-92) (Box 93, Folder 58)
    - Garwin-Gerry Debate (1992) (Box 95, Folder 21)
    - K. Gottfried (Box 95, Folder 26)
    - Autograph requests (Box 95, Folder 28-29)
    - Personal Security Questionnaire (1983) (Box 96, Folder 35)
    - Los Alamos History (1988-89) (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Proposed Movie on Los Alamos - Joffe (1989) (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Travel (1989-90) (Box 97, Folder 18)
    - Ron Lellis[?] - "Dinosaur Egg" (Box 99, Folder 23)
    - Harvard Commencement materials, 1958 (Box 116, Folder 17)
    - Photographs of Hans for Boehr Library (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Copy of White House picture, with printed signature of Jimmy Carter (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Photograph of the groundbreaking for the Holiday Inn (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Photograph of George Placec (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Edward Teller obituary, commemoration on DVD (DVD-1977), 2003 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Sabine Lee on Peierls and Hans, 2004 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Aspen Center for Physics, 2006 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Mary Palevsky interview with Bethe, 2000, 2004 (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica entry for Hans Bethe by Paul Ewald, 1974 (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Cornell preliminary reports, programs for Perkins' inauguration, centennial, faculty reports, 1962-1969 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Various newspaper and magazines, 2005-2006 (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Hans Bethe obituaries, 2005-2006 (Box 118, Folder 8-9)
    - Rose Bethe correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Unsorted files
    - Unsorted (1957-73) (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Unsorted (1972) (Box 83, Folder 37-39)
    - Unsorted (1973) (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Unsorted (1973-80) (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Unsorted (1974) (Box 84, Folder 5-10)
    - Unsorted (1974-76) (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Unsorted (1974-79) (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Unsorted (1976-77) (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Unsorted (1976-81) (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Unsorted (1977-79) (Box 84, Folder 15-18)
    - Unsorted (1977-79) (Box 84, Folder 19)
    - Unsorted (1977-79) (Box 84, Folder 20)
    - Unsorted (1978-79) (Box 84, Folder 21)
    - Unsorted (1979) (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Unsorted (1979-81) (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - Unsorted (1980) (Box 84-85, Folder 24)
    - Unsorted (1980-82) (Box 84, Folder 28)